VARUN S. VENKATESH

ACADEMIC RÉSUMÉ

Phone: (022) 383-7963 183 The Parade varun.venkatesh@gmail.com Island Bay, Wellington

https://varunsvenkatesh.github.io/

I am currently seeking a post-doctoral research role to further my skill sets in scientific research; specifically I wish to learn bioinformatics techniques to use in conjunction with my wet lab skills to answer biological questions.

What I can bring you is a wide variety of skills in molecular biology ranging from mammalian cell culture to microbiology and a strong ability in problem solving and critical analysis. In addition, I have considerable teaching experience at all levels of biology having lectured, led labs, coordinated tutorials, assisted in the development of teaching labs for multiple years.

Finally, I have significant lab management experience having been assistant lab manager to my supervisor for 4 years. In this capacity I ordered items for the lab, ensured equipment was well maintained and working, monitored and maintained lab compliance to standards and taught several junior students lab skills. My skill set would make me valuable to any lab.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy	Victoria University of Wellington,	Anticipated	
(Biomedical Sciences)	Thesis title: Investigating the role of the	2018	
	apelinergic system in glioblastoma	3.5 0010	
Bachelor of biomedical	Victoria University of Wellington,	May 2012	
Science (Hons)	Graduated with First Class honours		
HONOURS, AWARDS AND GRA	NTS		
Research for Life Grant		2017	
\$6000 to undertake research t			
glioblastoma growth.			
		-01-	
PGSA Landers Postgraduat	2017		
The Landers Award is awarded to an individual who has provided outstanding			
	improve the experience of the postgraduate		
student experience.			
Victoria University of Wellington Doctoral Submission Scholarship		2016	
Victoria University of Welli	ngton Doctoral Scholarshin	2013-2016	
A three-year grant to undertal	2013 2010		
• •	os are awarded on academic merit and are open to	`	
New Zealand and international	<u>.</u>	,	
110 w Zealand and Internationa	ii students in any discipline.		
Otago University Summer S	2011		

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

When you list courses, include a brief description so that the course can be compared to a similar course at another university. You might want to include the typical number of students in the course as well as list your responsibilities such as developing course materials, lecturing, grading, developing the syllabus, etc. How you decide to list or group your courses, skills, teaching methods, roles, and responsibilities will depend on your amount of experience. The examples below are just a few ideas.

Victoria University of Wellington, New Zealand March 2017 to June 2018 Lecturer (Neuroscience), School of Biological Sciences

- Taught the neurobiology section of Biol 114, an undergraduate course averaging over 300 students per semester
- Developed a new neurobiology lab surrounding the effect of nicotine on cricket neuronal function.
- Developed quizzes, exams, and homework

Victoria University of Wellington, New Zealand March 2017 to July 2017 **Lecturer (Carbohydrate metabolism)**, School of Biological Sciences

- Taught the neurobiology section of Biol 114, an undergraduate course averaging over 300 students per semester.
- Developed quizzes, exams, and a new lab with the assistance of Dr Paul Teesdale Spittle
- Coordinated grading and labs with a team of 6 teaching assistants

Victoria University of Wellington, New Zealand March 2012 to December 2018 Teaching Assistant (Over 7 individual courses), School of Biological Sciences

- Taught over seven different courses as a TA and Head TA in some cases with varying content including:
 - o Cell regulation (Biol 339)
 - o Genes and Genomes (Biol 340)
 - o Biology of Animals (Biol 114)
 - o Cell Biology (Biol 111)
 - o Advanced Physiology (Biol 335)
 - Physiology and Pharmacology (Biol 243)
 - Human Sexuality and Reproduction (Biol 116)
- Duties included organization of new TA's, marking of reports, collation of grades and the leading of labs. Detials presented here: (Website link)

MOLECULAR SKILLS

I have a wide range of molecular biology skills and techniques abut an also highly adept at learning new techniques and relish these opportunities.

Western blotting Microbiology

PCR including qPCR Nucleic Acid Isolation

Confocal Microscopy Flow cytometry

Mammalian cell culture Immunohistochemistry and immunocytochemistry

Basic cloning techniques Protein isolation

In vitro assays such as: wound healing Basic aptamer generation

COMPUTER SKILLS

I have a strong knowledge of basic PAS statistical software (PRISM and SPSS) and standard Microsoft products. In addition I am comfortable using open source software such as ImageJ and Inkscape. I am currently developing my programming, large dataset analysis and statistical skills. Through learning the language R.

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

School of biological Sciences Coding Club	Noting a changing need for biologists to understand how to programme, I established a coding club in the school of biological sciences with a colleague to facilitate student learning. This also resulted in the co-organisation of a Combine software carpentry symposium.	2016 - 2017
School of Biological Sciences ambassador - Open Days at VUW		2013 - 2017
School of biological Sciences Journal Club (Co-founder)	Established a journal club in the SBS to keep students abreast of current paradigms in science.	2014 - 2015
Student representative on the School of Biological Sciences Research Committee	In this role I facilitate the communication between students and members of the research committee regarding issues surrounding research at The Victoria University Wellington School of Biological Sciences (VUW SBS). During this time I have also presented ideas surrounding the improvement of postgraduate performance in the VUW SBS	2013 - 2014

REFERENCES

Dr Darren Day – Primary PhD Supervisor

darren.day@vuw.ac.nz Phone: 04 463 6087

Professor John Miller – Secondary PhD Supervisor

john.h.miller@vuw.ac.nz

Phone: 04 463 6082